mycitydeal.co.uk 2014-06-26

# Groupon - Local Deals, Goods, and Getaways

This website is owned and operated by MyCityDeal Limited (t/a Groupon UK). Groupon UK operates a centralised marketing platform that allows certain sellers to sell items on the website. Your personal information related to a purchase will be processed by the applicable seller in accordance with the privacy statements listed below:

  * Groupon UK: This privacy policy applies in respect of your use of the Groupon UK site and service, as well as your purchase of vouchers from Groupon UK.
  * Groupon International Travel: This privacy policy applies in respect of your purchase of a reservation from Groupon International Travel.
  * Groupon Goods Global: This privacy policy applies in respect of your purchase of goods from Groupon Goods Global.

##  **Groupon UK Privacy Policy**

 **We protect your personal information and data**  

 **1\. Protecting You**

The Groupon Site www.groupon.co.uk is operated by MyCityDeal Limited (t/a Groupon UK). MyCityDeal Limited (" **Groupon UK** ", " **we** ," " **us** ," " **our** ") is committed to protecting your privacy. We are registered with the Information Commissioner’s office and our registration number is Z2232703. We will only use the information that we collect about you lawfully (in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable data protection laws in the UK).

Please note that use of the Site by you and any services offered by Groupon UK are subject to this privacy policy (the " **Policy** "), our [Cookies Policy](http://www.groupon.co.uk/cookie-policy) and to the Site’s [Terms of Use](http://www.groupon.co.uk/terms_and_conditions) of. Please also note that this Policy also applies to you in respect of any Voucher you purchase from Groupon UK. When you use the Site but purchase from a seller other than Groupon UK, this Policy will apply to you in addition to the privacy statement that a seller will also have (which will be available for you to read and review on the Site).

Where this Policy uses a word starting with a capital letter, that term will be defined in the [Terms of Use](http://www.groupon.co.uk/terms_and_conditions) of or elsewhere in this Policy.

Our Policy explains what information we collect, how we use and/or share this information, and how such information is maintained. By using this Site or any other services of Groupon UK, you signify your acceptance of this Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy you should not use this Site or the services of Groupon UK. Please note that this Policy applies with respect to the information collected on the Site and through any other contact we have with you (irrespective of whether you have made a purchase from Groupon UK, Groupon International Travel or any other seller).

Our Policy aims to ensure that any information you provide to us remains private and secure. To reassure you, below we provide details of the information you provide to us, and how it will and, more importantly, will not be used. We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent. The information we hold will be accurate and up to date. You can check the information that we hold about you by contacting us (and there may be an administrative fee payable for this). If you find any inaccuracies we will delete or correct it promptly.

 **2\. Personally Identifiable Information - that we collect**

We collect personally identifiable information (" **PII** ") that is volunteered during registration or in response to specific information requests explicitly presented to you.

When using the Site, we may also collect your IP (Internet Protocol) address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the Site. An IP address is a number that is assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. Your IP address is also used to help identify you during a particular session and to gather broad demographic data.

We may ask for your e-mail address during your use of the Site. Also, to purchase anything from the Site or to deal with any purchase in some way (such as to arrange delivery of products or services through a third party) you may be requested to provide any or all of the following PII: first and last name, postal address, e-mail address, date of birth, telephone number and details of a payment mechanism, such as credit card details.

 **3\. Use and Sharing of PII**

All PII is retained in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable data protection laws in the UK.

We use PII:

• to provide you with information about Groupon UK and/or other companies in the Groupon Group;

• to provide you with the services on the Site and otherwise;

• to facilitate services which are directly related to services on the Site;

• to facilitate your redemption of vouchers with the suppliers of products and services for which those vouchers can be exchanged (i.e. “Merchants”);

• to facilitate the fulfilment of the products and/or services you have purchased via the Site (from or through any sellers on the Site);

• to measure, record and report on the performance of Merchants or other businesses who supply or provide products and/or services to individuals who make purchases on the Site;

• to market ourselves, other companies in the Groupon Group and the Merchants or other businesses we feature on the Site to you, including personalised marketing for the services we provide and any items that may be offered for sale on the Site or otherwise, all based on variables such as your stated or anticipated interests, gender or location;

• to analyse the effectiveness of, and to improve, our marketing campaigns (and any marketing campaigns we may conduct on behalf of companies in the Groupon Group); and

• to enhance the information we have about you to better align our personalised marketing with your interests.

We make PII available:

1\. within Groupon UK;

2\. to other companies in the Groupon Group:

• within the European Economic Area;

• outside of the European Economic Area but in countries which provide an adequate level of data protection according to the European Commission; and

• outside of the European Economic Area but in countries which do not provide an adequate level of protection through the Safe Harbour certification (if sent to the United States) and/or through the conclusion of data privacy contracts with clauses based on the models of the European Commission;

3\. to Merchants to facilitate the redemption of vouchers with the Merchant or to facilitate your receipt of the products and/or services you purchased from the Site; and in both cases to provide feedback to the Merchants or other sellers on the Site based on customer survey results, including, at our discretion, any comments made about a Merchant's performance; and

4\. to our agents and subcontractors to help us with any of our uses of your data set out in this Policy. For example, we may use third parties to provide us with marketing or customer service assistance and we use third parties to securely process payments.

Please note that for purposes of point 3 (merchants and businesses) and point 4 (our agents and subcontractors) above, we may send your personal data to these third party businesses and entities even if they are outside of the EEA. Some places outside of the EEA may not have adequate data protection laws at all or may offer differing levels of protection of personal information which are not as high as in the UK. By submitting PII to us, you acknowledge that we cannot be held responsible for any use of your data by such third parties who receive and process your data.

We also always reserve the right to disclose PII in order to:

a. comply with applicable laws;  
b. respond to governmental enquiries (or enquiries from a legal, governmental or quasi-governmental or local authority agency or Internet protection agency of any type);  
c. comply with a valid legal process or procedure; or  
d. protect our rights or property, this Site, and/or other users of this Site.

 **  
However, other than as set out above, it is our policy not to sell or pass any PII to any other organisations unless we are required to do so for fraud prevention and detection.**

 **Importantly, other than to other companies in the Groupon Group, we will never sell or rent your PII to anyone else for their marketing purposes without your consent.**

Please note that provided we have used your data in the ways set out in this Policy, we are not responsible for what third parties who receive your data do with it.

 **4\. Emails, telephone calls and texts**

Please note that we may email you for the following purposes:

• as part of the services offered by us. For example, we send (or may send) emails to you in some of the following example circumstances:   
  \- after registration, notifying you of your account details;   
  \- as reminder emails about the services we offer (particularly if you have not used them yet or not used them for a while);   
  \- to send you information on Vouchers or other products and/or services which you have asked for;   
• as a personalised newsletter;   
• as promotional emails for any of the items which can be purchased on the Site;   
• as an opportunity to provide feedback about a particular Merchant’s service or particular products and/or services you may have purchased from other businesses; and   
• to offer related services to you from the Groupon Group of companies.

 **However, in terms of any marketing or promotional emails we may send, we will always give you the chance to opt-out (or unsubscribe) from them in the future.** Please note that we may telephone you or send you texts (SMS) to your mobile phone for the following purposes:

 ** ** • as part of the services offered by us. For example, we telephone or text you in some of the following example circumstances:    
  \- as reminder calls or texts about the services we offer (particularly if you have not used them yet or not used them for a while);   
  \- to send you information on Vouchers or other products and/or services which you have asked for; 

 **We will always give you the chance to opt-out from receiving telephone calls or texts in the future.  
**

 **

5\. Security and retention

**

The PII which we hold will be held securely within our systems in accordance with our internal security policy and the law. We hold data until 3 years after it is last accessed or used by us.

Regarding information transmitted between the Site and/or users, while we take reasonable precautions to safeguard this information, we may be unable to prevent unauthorised access to such information by third parties or inadvertent disclosure of such information during transit. Users acknowledge this risk when communicating with the Site.

 **6\. Transfer in Certain Circumstances**  
If there is a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganisation or liquidation of Groupon UK then, in our sole discretion, we may transfer, sell or assign information collected on and through this Website (including, without limitation, PII and other information), to one or more relevant third parties.

 **7\. Customer Service**

If you have any questions or concerns, please feel free to contact us at [support@groupon.co.uk](mailto:support@groupon.co.uk).

 **8\. Changes to this Policy**

Please note that this Policy, along with the [Terms of Use](http://www.groupon.co.uk/terms_and_conditions) , forms part of the agreement between you and us regarding the services provided by Groupon UK. We may, from time to time, amend this Policy, in whole or part, in our sole discretion. Any changes to this Policy will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised policy on the Site. (Depending on the nature of the change, we may announce the change: (a) on the home page of the Site, (b) by email, if we have your email address, or (c) in some other way.) In any event, by continuing to use the Site following any changes, you will be deemed to have agreed to such changes. If you do not agree with the terms of this Policy, as it may be amended from time to time, in whole or part, you must terminate your use of the Site and any services offered by Groupon UK.

************************************************************************************************************************

##  **GROUPON INTERNATIONAL TRAVEL PRIVACY STATEMENT**

 **Please note that this privacy statement only applies to you if you purchase a reservation from Groupon International Travel, GmbH.**

 **Effective Date: 19.06.2013**

 **Last Updated: 19.06.2013**

This Privacy Statement ( **"Privacy Statement"** ) explains how Groupon International Travel GmbH, with registered address at Freier Platz 10, 8200 Schaffhausen, Switzerland ( **"Groupon Travel"** , **"us"** , **"our"** , and **"we"** ), processes and uses information about you. This Privacy Statement applies to information we collect when you interact with the Groupon UK website featured on www.groupon.co.uk (the **"Site"** ) by purchasing reservations sold by Groupon Travel. The Site is owned and operated by MyCityDeal Limited (t/a Groupon UK), an English company, with a registered address at Seal House, 1 Swan Lane, London, EC4R 3TN ( **"Groupon UK"** ).

This Privacy Statement was adopted as of the "Effective Date" above, and may be amended from time to time. If we make any material changes we will notify you, either by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or through other appropriate means. You can determine when this version of the Privacy Statement was most recently adopted by referring to the date it was "Last Updated" above.

### 1\. Personal data collected

Groupon UK owns and operates this Site. It is the data owner in respect of all information you provide or is made available about you when you interact with the Site. Your customer relationship is with Groupon UK and they process your personal data in relation to your interaction and customer relationship with the Site. This includes your name, email address, gender, location and other information, but always according to applicable UK privacy law and as described by Groupon UK's Privacy Policy. Groupon UK also provides Groupon Travel with technical and organisational services in relation to the promotion and marketing of the supplier's offers through the Site and performs other commercial and administrative marketing support services. For these activities Groupon UK acts as data processor.

Groupon Travel is the data owner in respect of data it collects when you make reservations on the Site. This includes your name, email address and travel dates. We directly process your data in accordance with the Swiss Federal Data Protection Act of 19 June 1992 and its ordinances (the "Privacy Law"). In line with the Privacy Law, we may also receive your personal data collected online (i.e. through websites) and offline (i.e. at physical sale points) in relation to activities related to your use or experience with your reservation.

### 2.How we use information - purposes and conditions of processing

We process data mainly through electronic means according to defined procedures and logics for the following purposes:

• To process the reservations you purchase from us through the Site and manage everyday business needs functional to sale and post-sale, such as performance of contract obligations, fraud prevention, invoicing, managing of refunds and returns, providing the requested support (such as customer support), etc.;

• When you contact us, to manage your requests, questions and communications; and

• To comply with laws, regulations and legislation, and enforcement of our judicial rights.

We need to use your personal data for the above-mentioned purposes in order to comply with the law, fulfil your reservation, and otherwise to provide the services or customer support that you request.

Please note that if you make a reservation for individuals other than yourself, it is your responsibility to ensure that you comply with the Privacy Law in respect of your submission to us of their personal information. In particular it is your responsibility to ensure other individuals on whose behalf you make a reservation have given consent for us to process their data in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

### 3\. When and Why Groupon Travel Discloses Information

We are not in the business of selling or renting personal data. We will not share your personal data, except with your consent, as otherwise required by law or as otherwise described in this Privacy Statement. We disclose personal information to the below-listed categories of third parties, which act as data owners, processors or persons in charge of processing. We pass this information to third parties for the purposes identified above in section 2 and always in accordance with applicable privacy laws. We may pass or share your personal data:

• With affiliated and unaffiliated technical and organisational service providers relevant to our business. In this regard, for services functional to information management systems, management of the Site and customer support, we revert to Groupon, Inc., registered offices at 600 West Chicago Avenue, Chicago, Illinois - 60610, USA, and to Groupon UK, located in the UK. Transfer of personal data to the US is authorised under the Privacy Law since Groupon Inc. has adhered to the [Safe Harbor Principles](http://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=15342), while transfer to the UK is allowed as the European Commission has recognised that the UK is a country which provides an adequate level of data protection.

• To third parties to report or collect on debts owed to us or our suppliers or other business partners.

• As necessary to perform contractual obligations toward you with business partners to the extent you have purchased an accommodation reservation or other services from us and to be supplied by a business partner.

• In case of a merger, acquisition, transfer of assets or business assets, reorganization or other extraordinary operations in relation to potential purchasers and relevant consultants.

• To comply with legal orders and government requests, or as needed to support auditing, compliance, and corporate governance functions, including disclosure to law enforcement agencies, regulators, and courts.

• To combat fraud or criminal activity, and to protect our rights or those of our affiliates, business partners and users, or as part of legal proceedings affecting Groupon Travel.

We encourage suppliers and business partners to adopt and post privacy policies. However, while we share personal data with suppliers and business partners only for the above-mentioned purposes and under the above-mentioned conditions, their subsequent processing and use of personal data obtained through Groupon Travel is governed by their own privacy policies and practices and not subject to our control.

In particular, given the nature of our business, it is likely some recipients may be located outside the European Union, in countries with an inadequate level of data protection under the Privacy Law. You recognise and understand that when you make a reservation, we will pass your personal information to the supplier or business partner who is responsible for fulfilling your reservation so that they may provide you with the accommodation you have reserved.

Please also note that our personnel charged with processing and the processor (if applicable) have access to data on a need-to-know basis.

### 4\. Security of Personal Data

We process data mainly in electronic form in line with the Privacy Law security requirements; Groupon Travel has implemented an information security program that contains administrative, technical and physical controls that are designed to reasonably safeguard your personal data, including industry-standard encryption technology.

### 5.Your Rights in relation to Personal Data; Contact

You can exercise your rights of access at any time. Such access rights include, for example, your right to obtain a description of the personal data we hold about you, to verify such personal data including its origin and accuracy, to ask us to amend or delete certain information, or to opt-out of certain types of processing. You may enforce your privacy rights by reviewing the information in your account, emailing us at privacy@groupon.com, or writing us at: Groupon International Travel, Freier Platz 10, Schaffhausen, Switzerland. You may write or email us also in case of questions or requests on this Privacy Statement and our privacy practices.

While we are ready to assist you, we cannot always delete records of past interactions and transactions. For example, we are required to retain records relating to previous purchases for financial reporting and compliance reasons.

### 6\. Retention of Personal Data

We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to perform our obligations to you as specified in our [Reservation Terms of Sale](http://www.groupon.co.uk/terms_and_conditions#rtos) and as required by applicable law.

### 7\. Websites of Third Parties

This Privacy Statement only addresses the collection, processing and use (including disclosure) of your personal data by us when you purchase an accommodation reservation from Groupon Travel or interact with customer support relating to a purchase from Groupon Travel. Groupon Travel is neither the owner nor the operator of the Site and the Site may provide links to other websites. These websites have their own privacy policies and personal information collection, processing, use, and disclosure practices. Our suppliers and business partners may also have their own privacy policies. We encourage you to familiarise yourself with the privacy policies provided by these other parties prior to providing them with personal information or taking advantage of a sponsored offer or promotion; Groupon Travel is responsible only in relation to what it is described in this Privacy Statement.

************************************************************************************************************************

##  **GROUPON GOODS GLOBAL PRIVACY STATEMENT**

 **Please note that this privacy statement only applies to you if you purchase a product from Groupon Goods Global GmbH.**

 **Effective Date: 1.09.2013**

 **Last Updated: 1.09.2013**

This Privacy Statement (“ **Privacy Statement** ”) explains how Groupon Goods Global GmbH, with registered address at Freier Platz 10, 8200 Schaffhausen, Switzerland (“ **Groupon Goods** ”, “ **us** ”, “ **our** ”, and “ **we** ”), processes and uses information about you. This Privacy Statement applies only to information we process in order to facilitate your purchase of products sold by us on the Groupon UK website, featured on www.groupon.co.uk (the “ **Site”** ).  The Site is owned and operated by Groupon UK, an English company, with a registered address at Seal House, 1 Swan Lane, London EC4R 3TN (“ **Groupon UK** ”).

This Privacy Statement was adopted as of the “Effective Date” above, and may be amended from time to time. In the event of a material change, we may notify you of such changes. You can determine when this version of the Privacy Statement was most recently adopted by referring to the date it was “Last Updated” above. ****

 **1\. Personal data collected**

Groupon Goods is the data owner in respect of your personal data that is necessary to provide you with the products you purchased from us on the Site. This includes information such as your name and delivery address. Groupon Goods directly processes your data in accordance with the Swiss Federal Data Protection Act of 19 June 1992 and its ordinances (the “ **Privacy Law** ”). ****

Please note that Groupon UK is the data owner in respect of all information you provide or is made available about you when you interact with the Site. This includes, for example, information necessary to create a Groupon account or to subscribe to email marketing. Your customer relationship is with Groupon UK, which processes your personal information in accordance with applicable privacy law and itsPrivacy Statement.

 **2\. How Groupon Goods uses information**

Groupon Goods processes your personal data in order to fulfill your order. This consists of information related to:

• the delivery and shipment of the products you have purchased from us; and

• managing everyday business needs functional to sale and post-sale.

Groupon Goods will also process your data in order to comply with laws, regulations and legislation, as well as enforcement of our judicial rights. Please note that if you purchase products for individuals other than yourself, it is your responsibility to ensure that you comply with the Privacy Law in respect of your submission to us of their personal information. ****

**3\. When and Why Groupon Goods Discloses Information**

We are not in the business of selling or renting personal data. When we process your personal data for the purposes set out in section 2 above, we may pass or share your personal data with the following third parties, as may be necessary from time to time:

• With affiliated and unaffiliated technical and organisational service providers relevant to our business. This includes Groupon UK and Groupon, Inc. Groupon, Inc. has its registered offices at 600 West Chicago Avenue, Chicago, Illinois - 60610, USA. Transfer of personal data to Groupon UK is authorised as it is within the EU. Transfer to the US is authorised under the Privacy Law since Groupon Inc. has adhered to the Safe Harbor Principles - <http://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=15342>. 

• To third parties to report or collect on debts owed to us or our suppliers or other business partners. 

• To third parties in order for us to to perform contractual obligations toward you, combat fraud or criminal activity, or as part of legal proceedings affecting us. 

• To law enforcement officers or other government officials, to comply with legal orders and government requests, or as needed to support auditing, compliance, and corporate governance functions.

Please note that it is likely some recipients of your data may be located outside of Switzerland or the European Union, in countries with an inadequate level of data protection. You recognise and understand that when you purchase a product, we may pass your personal information to a service provider or business partner who supports delivery of your product to you and that this service provider or business partner may be located (or process your personal data) outside of Switzerland or the European Union.

 **4\. Security of Personal Data**

We process data mainly in electronic form in line with the Privacy Law security requirements; Groupon Goods has implemented an information security programme that contains administrative, technical and physical controls that are designed to reasonably safeguard your personal data, including industry-standard encryption technology.

 **5\. Retention of Personal Data and Your Rights in relation to Personal Data**

We will retain your personal data for as long as necessary to perform our contractual obligations to you and as required by applicable law. Should you wish to know more about the personal data we have about you, you can exercise your rights of access at any time. Should you wish to do so, please contact us at <http://www.groupon.co.uk/customer_support>. You may also write to us us at: Groupon Goods Global GmbH, Freier Platz 10, Schaffhausen, Switzerland.

Please note that while we are ready to assist you, we cannot always delete records of past interactions and transactions. For example, we are required to retain records relating to previous purchases for financial reporting and compliance reasons. ****
